<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></title><description><![CDATA[aspiring actuary // uc berkeley]]></description><link>http://dsury.com</link><image><url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dsuryakusuma/dsuryakusuma.github.io/gh-pages/images/IMG_7034.jpg</url><title>Daniel Suryakusuma</title><link>http://dsury.com</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 04:15:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://dsury.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Resume: Daniel Suryakusuma]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p><a href="https://resume.dsury.com/">Resume available in (.pdf) here.</a><br>
Contact: dsuryakusuma(at)berkeley.edu | 909.569.5177<br>
&#160;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_actuarial_exams">Actuarial Exams</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Exam P/1: Passed first sitting | July 2017<br>
Exam FM/2: Passed first Sitting | Oct 2017<br>
Exam IFM/3: Sitting | Nov 2018</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_education">Education</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>University of California, Berkeley | Berkeley, CA<br>
B.A. Applied Mathematics | Dec 2019 (Expected)</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>University of California, Berkeley - Extension | Berkeley, CA
C.P. Certificate Program in Paralegal Studies | Jan 2017</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_skills">Skills</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Analytical: Excel | MATLAB | R | VBA | SQL | SAS<br>
&#160;&#160;^ The Infinite Actuary - Technical Skills Course<br>
Programming: Python | Java | HTML| CSS | Javascript<br>
Computer: Salesforce | Excel | Access | SQL | Adobe InDesign/Photoshop</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_professional_experience">Professional Experience</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Berkeley Center for Law &amp; Technology | UC Berkeley School of Law<br>
Web Development Lead, Administrative Assistant | Aug 2013 - May 2015</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Synthesized over 500 datasets into various structured databases of client accounts, implementing Salesforce programs and Excel spreadsheets for optimized parsing efficiency</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Professionally managed legal projects funded by local law firms, highlighting groundbreaking technology law cases, and connecting firms and patent boutiques with law school students and intellectual property scholars</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Presented data infographics and posters at symposiums and conferences</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Berkeley Technology Review | Berkeley, CA<br>
Contributing Editor, Web Developer | Sep 2014 - May 2015</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Created and published articles on privacy, copyright law, and disruptive technologies</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Merged elements of different web application platforms into intuitive and reactive user interface, using Drupal, Node.js, and WordPress</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cultivated and closely managed team of writers through rigorous editorial process</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Relay for Life, American Cancer Society | Walnut, CA<br>
Logistics Committee Chair | Sep 2011 - May 2013</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Individually conducted business meetings with corporate leads and intercity officials to close sponsorship deals and authorized use of public space</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Managed expenditures and donations to meet required event specifications</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_awards_certification">Awards / Certification</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Certified Paralegal | Jan 2017<br>
Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program Scholar | Jan 2017<br>
Thomas Stern Calculus Excellence Award | May 2013<br>
AP National Scholar Award | July 2013</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2018/12/16/Resume.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2018/12/16/Resume.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><category><![CDATA[Resume]]></category><category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Passed FM]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Just passed FM! I’ve been so busy lately with a great mix of things, but it’s a huge relief to pass my second exam.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I posted a thank you note to <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/actuary/">Reddit</a> to show my gratitude towards the community that helped helped me get started. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/actuary/comments/763g62/the_ractuary_effect/">For detailed information, find emotional post here</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At this point I know I&#8217;ll work to make this website informational and educational to help fellow aspiring actuaries grow.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I’ll revisit my notes on P/1 and FM/2 to make study notes to supplement M Finan’s texts (which are fantastic resources to learn the material).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The first two preliminary exams P and FM can easily and effectively be studied for completely free of cost, using M Finan’s texts and other free open source guides just as long as people keep to the test syllabus and learning objectives.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>To people who are contemplating an actuarial route, I do suggest that they dive into the test material and possess the willingness to commit to test preparation.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/10/13/Passed-FM.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/10/13/Passed-FM.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Exams]]></category><category><![CDATA[FM/2]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Determinants of Interest Rates]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div id="preamble">
<div class="sectionbody">
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This second installment of study notes for exam FM/2 covers determinants of interest rates. The objective like the first installment covering <a href="http://daniel.financial/2017/09/22/Interest-Rate-Swaps.html">interest rate swaps</a> is to provide students studying for the FM exam with the key points and take-aways from the topic at hand. Determinants of Interest Rates is tested on the new syllabus for exam FM/2 with a weight of 0~10% according to the learning objectives syllabus.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The full document from the SOA can be found here <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjh3Pbyx8bWAhWmhFQKHSRwBr0QFggoMAA&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.soa.org%2FFiles%2FEdu%2F2017%2Ffm-determinants-interest-rates.pdf&amp;usg=AFQjCNFVcxnZC-IKvSdTHRQ8tIc_qnOcng">.pdf download</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_federal_funds_rate">Federal funds rate</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Interest rate for one bank to borrow from another bank&#8217;s reserve (to meet minimum reserve requirements). Adjusted to approximately match "federal funds target rate."</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_discount_rate">Discount rate</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Rate that banks can borrow at, <strong>directly</strong> from federal reserve bank.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_libor_london_interbank_offered_rate">LIBOR (London Interbank Offered Rate)</h3>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>International interest rates for short-tern loans.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_federal_reserve_bank_us_s_central_banks">Federal Reserve Bank (US&#8217;s central banks)</h3>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Board of Governors</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>12 regional reserve banks</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>FOMC (Federal Open Market Committee) sets federal funds target rate to stabilize: employment rate, stable prices, moderate long-term interest rates</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_bond_concepts">Bond Concepts</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>call provision:</strong> option for issuer to pay (above par) before maturity date</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>put provision:</strong> option for holder to sell (below par) to issuer before maturity.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>These give option to re-negotiate a new bond at better interest rate, following liquidity preference theory and opportunity cost theory.</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>revenue bonds:</strong> example - contingent on tolls for drivers on bridge, charges to homeowners for water services, etc</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>general obligation bonds:</strong> backed by general taxing authority or state/local government</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_interest_concepts">Interest Concepts</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>yield</strong> with risk of default should be <em>higher</em> to compensate for this risk</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>"prime rate"</strong> - rate charged to bank&#8217;s best and most creditworthy customers. only a few entities receive this rate, but it is used as a benchmark for comparison.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_treasury_bills_t_bills">Treasury Bills (T-Bills):</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>1 year or less term</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>no interest</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>sold at discount</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>quoted with simple discount &amp; actual/360</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sect2">
<h3 id="_treasury_notes_bonds_t_bond">Treasury Notes/Bonds (T-Bond):</h3>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>2~30 years term</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>semi-annual interest coupons</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>sold at or near par</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>quoted with semi-annual compounding</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/09/24/Determinants-of-Interest-Rates.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/09/24/Determinants-of-Interest-Rates.html</guid><category><![CDATA[FM/2]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interest Rate Swaps]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is the first installment of additional study notes for exam FM/2, on interest rate swaps. The objective of this study note is to provide other students with a streamlined review of new material tested for the exam in the new syllabus starting July 2017.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The full SOA article on interest rate swaps <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjqyNiXw8bWAhXCxFQKHSOZCekQFggoMAA&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.soa.org%2FFiles%2FEdu%2F2016%2Fedu-2016-fm-25-17-interest-rate-swaps.pdf&amp;usg=AFQjCNF8d9rogP9Da88d-TurdDTtzDPtAw">can be found here (.pdf download)</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The topic of interest rate swaps is tested with a weight of 0~10% of the total exam according to the syllabus &amp; learning objectives.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A <strong>swap</strong> is an agreement to exchange cash flows at specific future times according to specified rules. This is equivalent to a series of forward contracts combined in one contract, or a portfolio of future contracts.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>A <strong>commodity swap</strong> consists of one party selling commodity (or cash equivalent) and the counterparty paying for the commodity (the buyer). The contract must specify: type, quality of commodity, and how to settle the contract. These are usually associated with energy-related products like oil, and have no governmental oversight. Usually, a "swap dealer" is involved between the two counterparties and earns the "bid-ask" spread as a commission.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An <strong>interest rate swap</strong> is a means of converting (1) a series of future interest payments that <em>vary</em> with changes in interest rates (AKA floating payments) with (2) series of <em>fixed</em> level payments (i.e. swap rate), or vice versa.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>An <strong>asset swap</strong> is an interest rate swap used to convert cash flows from underlying security (i.e. bond) from <em>fixed coupon</em> to <em>floating coupon</em>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Swaps do not necessarily have to start right away, they can be deferred (i.e. settled now, and the first term&#8217;s interest rate is locked, then the floating payments depend on the annualized interest rates when the deferred time is past).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The floating stream of payments are determined using a benchmark such as LIBOR, the London Interbank Offer Rate.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Definitions:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>r_t = spot interest rate for period of t years</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>P_t = (1 + r_t)^(-t) = PV of payment of 1 at time t AKA price of a ZCB (zero coupon bond) that matures to value of 1 at end of t years</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>f_[t1, t2] = forward interest rate</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Q_t = notional amount for settlement</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>R = "swap rate"</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Concept:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>PV(Interest to be paid on variable interest rate loan) = PV(Interest to be paid on fixed interest rate loan)</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Equations:
(subscripts are left out but variables correspond to definitions above)</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>R = Sum[Q*f*P]/Sum[Q*P]</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>And if Q is constant,</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>R = (P_t0 - P_tn)/(Sum[P_ti])</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The forward rate ( f_[t1, t2] ) can be calculated as follows:</p>
</div>
<div class="listingblock">
<div class="content">
<pre class="highlight"><code>f = [ (1 + r_t2)^t2 / (1 + r_t1)^t1 ] -1</code></pre>
</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>For more information, see the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjqyNiXw8bWAhXCxFQKHSOZCekQFggoMAA&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.soa.org%2FFiles%2FEdu%2F2016%2Fedu-2016-fm-25-17-interest-rate-swaps.pdf&amp;usg=AFQjCNF8d9rogP9Da88d-TurdDTtzDPtAw">full SOA document</a>. Specific examples of calculations are given and are invaluable for exam preparation.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/09/22/Interest-Rate-Swaps.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/09/22/Interest-Rate-Swaps.html</guid><category><![CDATA[FM/2]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A First Look: Health & Benefits]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I attended a CAL informational presentation from <a href="https://www.mercer.com/">Mercer</a> from their San Francisco practice, which has about 100 people in their Health &amp; Benefits team, and about 30 people on the Wealth management team. Presenters included Tim Oakes, Wendy Tan, and Alexa Garzelli on the Health &amp; Benefits side, and Deidre Schelin and Marc Corbeil on the Wealth side. As it stands, Mercer&#8217;s strength is staying on top of the H&amp;B current trends and policy to stay at the top as an analytical professional services group in the field.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Mercer is one of 4 branches under the Marsh &amp; McLennan Companies, a parent professional services company offering services in risk management, insurance  brokerage, reinsurance services, management consulting, and investment consulting.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After the event, I had the opportunity to hand in my resume and speak closely with Wendy Tan, a CAL alum. We spoke about ASA and FSA exams, student life, recruitment at Mercer, Mercer&#8217;s study program and bonuses, and the interview process for internships both at Mercer and in general. A key item she mentioned is it can only help in interviews to understand more of the underlying policies and specifics behind H&amp;B insurance, for example, concepts like excise tax and stop loss for H&amp;B.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I asked her about the projects she works on, specifically the types of data she is handed and what analytical processing she performs on it, and what she ships out to other people after she&#8217;s completed her task. Wendy spoke a bit to this and also provided insight into the monthly and quarterly reports she prepares for, as well as the large deadlines she must meet&#8212;&#8203;namely the 1/1 new year day.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I’m getting to learn more about Health &amp; Benefits, as well as Wealth in terms of roles of an actuary. As I currently understand H&amp;B, from the presentation, it involves the following:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Benefit Strategy and Design</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Benefit Plan Management &amp; Brokerage</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Specialty Health &amp; Benefits</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>International Consulting</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Individual &amp; Voluntary Benefits</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Benefits Administration</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Tim Oakes highlighted H&amp;B under the above categories, adding to it that Benefit Strategy and Design is his favorite due to the active role actuaries play in the overall strategy and influence on design.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m still exploring the different areas of actuarial science, specifically between pursuing an FSA versus FCAS. However, attending this informational session with Mercer has opened my eyes to the neat work actuaries perform in the H&amp;B sector. On top of that, all the employees really make Mercer out to be a great place to work at in terms of overall happiness and teamwork and coordination across teams. I&#8217;m extremely glad I was able to get a better understanding of the technical details behind actuarial work for analysts and actuarial associates in H&amp;B. Looking forward to seeing them again at the CAL Actuarial Career Fair!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/09/14/Health-and-Benefits.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/09/14/Health-and-Benefits.html</guid><category><![CDATA[CAL]]></category><category><![CDATA[Mercer]]></category><category><![CDATA[Info_Session]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Actuarial Career Panel - Fall 2017]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Thursday evening was a memorable one for me. I had the privilege of hearing from actuarial analysts from different companies around the bay area in different fields speak bits about their careers, their day-to-day, and tips and advice as to how to move forward in the actuarial career path.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Moderated by EVP Jackson Meyers, CAL held a discussion with company representatives from <a href="https://www.mercer.com/">Mercer</a>, <a href="https://www.willistowerswatson.com/">Willis Towers Watson</a>, <a href="http://www.oliverwyman.com/index.html">Oliver Wyman</a>, <a href="http://us.milliman.com/">Milliman</a>, <a href="http://www.aon.com/default.jsp">Aon</a>, <a href="http://csaa-insurance.aaa.com/content/aaa-ie/b2c/en/homepage.html/">CSAA</a>, <a href="http://www.rael-letson.com/">Rael &amp; Letson</a>, <a href="https://www.ciginsurance.com/">Capital Insurance Group</a>, <a href="http://www.nicolayconsulting.com/">Nicolay Consulting</a>, and
<a href="https://www.deltadental.com/Public/index.jsp">Delta Dental</a>. Many of the speakers were Cal graduates and were able to answer specific questions and provide insight specific to the process of pursuing an actuarial career out of Cal.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>At the panel discussion, I directed the following questions to the actuarial analysts:</p>
</div>
<div class="olist arabic">
<ol class="arabic">
<li>
<p>Actuarial science is one of the highest-rated careers for many factors and reasons, mainly cited for it&#8217;s low-stress and higher happiness levels. In your personal cases, do you agree with that? What were situations like where there were more stressful moments on the job or projects?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For everyone who went to Cal, which were the most useful classes in terms of preparation for entry-level projects, whether technical or nontechnical, and VEE accredited or not?</p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The event introduced me to a good baseline of questions, including:</p>
</div>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>What sorts of experiences as a student do you think were most valuable?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>what things did you wish you did before entering?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What excites you about this position?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Is that the same as what convinced you to join?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there a project you&#8217;ve done that sticks out in your mind?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What project experience was the most valuable for you and why?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Could you talk to me a bit about the positions that are available, and what I might do in one of those roles?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How much would I be interacting with you if I were an intern?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do interns get placed on projects?</p>
<div class="ulist">
<ul>
<li>
<p>Do interns ever work together?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
</li>
<li>
<p>What experiences bestprepared you for your job?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are the core components of your job?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Could you describe a typical day in the life of Company X?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s the most challenging part of your job?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kind of problems do you face on a day-to-day basis?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s it like to work for this particular company?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;s a typical career path in this industry?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What&#8217;re some qualities and skills that you value in an intern? Are there any concrete actions you&#8217;d recommend I take to develop those right away?</p>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Extremely blessed to have this opportunity to hear from, speak with, and get to know a little more from these actuaries from different fields. I&#8217;m excited to see what&#8217;s ahead in store at CAL. I know this organization has a lot going for it. On a personal note, it&#8217;s been an incredibly busy week for me, but it&#8217;s been keeping me grounded continuing forward. I lost an item that&#8217;s incredibly valuable to me the night of the Actuarial Career Panel, and it did take a toll on my mood for the rest of the week and weekend. However, I&#8217;m taking things into a more constructive light, focusing more on what I can improve&#8212;&#8203;namely, appreciating what I do have and the people around me that make everything worth it for me. Again, huge thanks to everyone who&#8217;s there with me supporting me through all times.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/09/09/Actuarial-Career-Panel.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/09/09/Actuarial-Career-Panel.html</guid><category><![CDATA[CAL]]></category><category><![CDATA[Career_Panel]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Actuarial Exam! Passed Exam P/1]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Super stoked to receive a preliminary pass today for my first actuarial exam, Exam P/1. It&#8217;s not much, but it&#8217;s a huge step for me moving forward. I&#8217;ve been studying for a month and I&#8217;m really glad it went well. Next up for me will be FM/2 in October. It&#8217;ll be a grind, but I&#8217;m looking to challenge myself and push my limits and encourage myself to get started again with growing and learning. I&#8217;d really like to get these exams under my belt to help me in the internship application process.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Here&#8217;s why this small achievement is such a huge deal to me.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I started college at Berkeley, I was tended towards an engineering &amp; law school path. The friends who knew me best tried to dissuade me&#8212;&#8203;they always saw me as someone to pursue mathematics given how passionate I was about learning mathematics as well as mathematic pedagogy. The way I saw it was I wanted to become a patent attorney, where on a regular basis I&#8217;m constantly learning about new things (different devices and technologies) to understand the underlying claims in a patent. Then, I&#8217;d take what I learned and translate it into a "lecture" in the court room.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>This is directly analogous to the role of an actuary, from learning about the context of given data and using actuarial judgement to build models and present upon the resulting implications.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>As a freshman at Berkeley, I look up a web development job at the <a href="https://www.law.berkeley.edu/research/bclt/">Berkeley Center for Law &amp; Technology</a> and worked with wonderful staff, legal researchers, law students, and professors. It was incredibly enlightening of an experience and opened my eyes to more critical discussions around technology&#8212;&#8203;not just understanding what technology can do for us but understanding in what ways a policy framework has to be constructed to promote stability and nimble growth in disruptive tech sectors. It seemed plausible that I could find a genuine interest in Intellectual Property law. I explored the option further, but my gut feeling told me it never felt right.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>People say some things take time. I&#8217;m honestly so blessed to have support from my sisters and to be able to amend and continue to build up my relationship with my parents. Though it&#8217;s a work in progress, it&#8217;s evident that there is a big difference already.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Meeting new people and building my own support system and network of close friends has turned my life around. I owe it to those who truly believed in me even in my worst and darkest moments who have helped me re-kindle my self-confidence.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>When I believed no career could accomodate my difficult situation and interest in problem-solving, it was thanks to <a href="https://reddit.com/r/actuary">r/actuary</a> that I was able to find a triving and fantastic community of helpful professionals and students out there helping each other in the career path. Simple research helped me plan out so many things in my life this past half-year. I&#8217;m looking up confidently this time around, excited to challenge myself and keep on pushing on to get better at everything I do. I&#8217;ve realigned with myself which is an incredibly critical moment in my life. Like I&#8217;ve mentioned, it&#8217;s such a small feat that I&#8217;ve passed Exam P/1, but I&#8217;ll take any victories I can, and I&#8217;ll keep moving forward.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Next up, FM/2! Also, looking for study buddies if anyone&#8217;s looking for someone to chat with, debate or share discussions with, or anything :)</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://dsury.com/2017/07/21/First-Exam.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://dsury.com/2017/07/21/First-Exam.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Exams]]></category><category><![CDATA[Actuary]]></category><category><![CDATA[P/1]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Daniel Suryakusuma]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>